# **KUZIVANOV VALERII**

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Minsk, Belarus | email: valerii.kuzivanov@gmail.com | tg: @valerii\_kuzivanov

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced Software Engineer with 9 years of experience. Specializing in web technologies and distributed micro-service oriented architectures.

Primary language: Typescript. Secondary languages: Python, Go.

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Mysql, Redis, ClickHouse, Apache Druid.

Frontend: React.js, Vue.js, Svelte, Redux, Thunk, Vuex, Nuxt.js, Next.js.

Backend: Node.js/Deno/Bun (Express, Koa, Fastify, Nest, Hono), Socket.io, JSON-RPC, GraphQL, gRPC,

OpenAPI.

DevOps: Linux, Bash, Nginx, Ansible, Docker, SOPS, Docker rollout, AWS, GCP, Jenkins, Nomad, Consul,

Vault, Traefik, ELK, Bare metal.

Message Queues: Kafka, NATS, RabbitMQ.

Test toolkit: Jest, Sinon.js, Supertest, Autocannon.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Development Team Lead | IPPlum**

Aug 2022 - Present

- Technical leadership of a small team.
- Exploring the domain.
- · Planning the architecture.
- Slicing ideas into tasks and dispersing them among the team.
- · Delivering code to production.

Stack: React.js, Nest.js, GraphQL(Apollo), Jenkins, Microservices and GRPC, Postgres, ELK.

## **Software Engineer | Via Transportation**

Jun 2021 - Jun 2022

- Development of internal panel for transport operators.
- Improvement of functionality for processing and transferring data from bunch of downstream to higher services.

Stack: React.js(Redux, Thunk), Node.js(Serverless.js, KOA.js), AWS, Kubernetes, Jenkins.

#### Software Engineer | Wargaming

Apr 2020 - Jun 2021

- Development of interfaces for the game "World of Tanks".
- Development different web services.

Stack: React.js, Vue.js, Node.js, Python2-3, Flask, Sqlalchemy, Django.

## **Backend Node.js Developer | Intelligent Urban Systems**

Jan 2019 - Apr 2020

- Development of backend microservices with node.js for mobile applications and frontend panel.
- Building CI/CD, configuring fault tolerance and seamless deployment

Stack: Docker(Swarm, Compose, Traefik), Node.js(Express, Koa, Moleculer), PostgreSql, MongoDB, Redis, Socket.io, NATS MQ, Jenkins Cl, React.js, Next.js.

#### Full Stack Engineer | Play2Live

Jun 2018 - Jan 2019

- Development of public in-game chat for streaming platform.
- Architecture and logic for chat-bots and giveaway microservices.
- Participation in development of frontend.

Stack: Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Node.js, Socket.io, Jest, Sinon.js, Sentry.io, Postgresql, Redis, JSON-RPC, Docker, Jenkins, Rabbit MQ.

#### Full Stack Engineer | SIA "Random Solutions"

Jun 2017 - Jun 2018

- Development of the internal control system and public application part.
- Upgrade system from php/apache/backbone to Vue/node/nginx stack.

Stack: Vue.js, Angular 4, backbone.js, websocket.io, node.js(express.js + socket.io), Nginx, php, Apache.

### Full Stack Engineer | Sibers

Sep 2016 - Aug 2017

Outsource company, development of projects of varying complexity.

Stack: Symfony 3.2, Codelgniter 3, Kohana, Laravel 5, YII2, React.js v14, Angular.js 1.6, Angular 2.0, Wordpress(WPRest API, plugins and themes), Apache2, Nginx.

#### Web Software Developer | Iteg

Oct 2015 - Sep 2016

• Development and support government projects.

Stack: Kohana framework, Apache2, Codelgniter 3. SASS/stylus & grunt/gulp, jQuery.

## Web Software Developer | Atlas

Dec 2014 - Dec 2015

• Landing design, layout and creation of advertising products.

Stack: Wordpress, Joomla, jQuery, jQuery-UI, SASS/LESS, grunt, Kohana, Open Cart.

# **EDUCATION**

# **Baltic State Technical University "VOENMEH"**

Sep 2006 - Sep 2009

University of Engineering

• Bachelor's degree in automation industry and technology.

# **Academy of tourism Bishkek**

May 2009 - May 2013

Management University

• Bachelor's degree, Business Administration and Management.

# **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

- Languages: English, Russian.
- Citizenship of the republic of Kyrgyzstan